Within this task we have been given three
animations; these shall be running after
each other, and there's also a preview of
how this looks again on this URL here.
I open this one and start running it.
There's first, second, third animation
and then the animation stops.
The task is to reproduce
this sequence of actions.
We have already been given a scene which
is a definition for this animation.
When we run this one,
everything happens together.
Our task is now to separate the parts and to
have these animations run after each other.
In order to do this, we can, of course,
use guards selecting the time points.
So first of all, we have a first time
point, and we can figure out when to stop
by looking into the definitions of the
animations; by just reading here the code we see.
Here is already a guard given and
it says if t is less than two
then something happens, and
otherwise there's a blank.
We can use animation1 by giving
exactly this parameter here, that is,
saying t is less than two,
then animation t happens.
We proceed like this for all the parts
- of course, if I -
Well, let me do it straightforward by
just copying the parts in this case.
So if we say t is less than
3 - then this happens -
And if t - then have a look again -
is less than two - then this happens.
And then, of course, we need
an otherwise case for the end.
Well, if you have a look at this,
we see there - these parts are covered
and this is probably not what we want.
And if we run it, we will see that
our animation is not as expected.
Of course, the first animation
happens, but then suddenly jumps.
The third one - just part of it - and then
the ending happens, and this
is not what we want, obviously.
Instead, we think about these times here.
This is the duration of the animation.
When we want to have the second
animation have a duration of three,
but starting at two, then the ending
point, of course, is 2 plus 3, which is 5.
But we also have to consider that
the animation starts at time point 0.
So if we have this as a parameter for
the animation - we have to subtract
two in order to get the animation right.
Okay, this is what happens now at the moment.
But then we have to consider also that
- well, it's not perfect, because the
other cases are missing, and so -
but we also have to consider
what's written in this task.
Here it says animation 2 has something -
it has to be scaled by a size factor of
two, and therefore we can look
up in the API: search scaling.
There are actually two functions
'scaled' and 'dilated'.
Scaled is used for scaling differently across the
x and y directions, but we can use the 'dilated'
function because it scales uniformly in both
directions, and this is exactly what we want.
So we can just scale the
animation by using dilated 2
and then giving the animation the parameter t,
so that the animation returns a picture - and we
can scale pictures by using the 'dilated' function.
Now we can apply the same, as I said before,
for the third animation, where we say
this one has a time factor of three, so there's
a duration of three for this second animation.
Our animation shall begin at
eight - our third animation
Again, this one has a duration of two.
We have t less than two; this one has
a duration of three, so this one has
the starting point two plus three, which is five.
This one has a duration - this one
has a duration of two, which is - oh,
five plus two is seven - so all right - but
then animation three has also another condition.
And here it says it shall
be played at half speed.
So how do we do half speed?
Half speed is multiplying by 0.5;
that's something we have to do.
And we have to reduce t also by five - which
is the value up there - as we did here, right?
t minus five, but now we have another
issue because - now the animation time
- because of reducing the animation
speed - our animation time has doubled.
Because we are halving the animation time,
we are - doubling - or we are halving the
animation speed while
doubling the animation time.
So this has to be not seven, but nine.
Because we have not two added to five but
two times two, which is in the end nine.
So, and now if we apply this, then we see our
animation running smoothly through as required.
This is exactly as in the given animation, and
so we fulfilled the task and that's the end.